Sel Norman

971-344-7403 | Hillsboro, Oregon selnorman.developer@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Full stack developer skilled in mobile-first responsive design and test-driven development. Experienced with modern tooling and coding methodologies.

SKILLS

Proficient in creating interactive web apps and APIs using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES5, ES6 and JSX), JSON Web Tokens, React.js, React Native, React Router, and Redux on the front-end, with Node.js, Python, Passport.js, AWS Lambda, MongoDB and PostgreSQL, KNEX.js backends. Continuous Integration and testing experience using Mocha, Chai, Git/GitHub, Travis CI and Heroku.

PROJECTS

Delivery Tracking App https://github.com/selvinor/delivery-tracking-client React, React Router, Redux, Node, Express, Mongo

A responsive web app that provides order pickup and delivery routing and tracking with a central depot and drivers.

AWS IoT Provisioning https://github.com/selvinor/aws-iot-provisioning Python, AWS Lambda, AWS DynamoDB

Automates provisioning of IoT devices. The device sends it's thing name to an API gateway. If the device has the permission to be provisioned it receives as a result, the region, iot endpoint, private key and certificate. With this information the device is able to connect to the endpoint where it has been provisioned and may publish data.

AWS IoT Device Manager https://github.com/selvinor/aws-iot-device-manager React Native, Expo, ReactHooks, Amplify, AWD Cloud Formation, Cognito

A responsive mobile app that updates AWS IoT devices with reference values of plant attributes and optimal ranges for temperature, ph, salts for comparison with plant sensor readings and trigger responses.

Blooms Subscription Service https://blooms-pdx.herokuapp.com/ React, React Router, Redux, Node, Express, Mongo A responsive web app that lets you send flowers to to a recipient at a residence or business according to a schedule.

Cozy Spaces https://cozy-spaces-client.herokuapp.com/

React, React Router, Redux, Node, Express, Mongo, Google Map API

Cozy Spaces is focused on bringing a warm glow to life through curating truly cozy spaces, especially for anyone experiencing cold climates, and/or nostalgia of a cozier time.

is an app that allows people to find and recommend cozy spots to hang out in their vicinity

Emoji Madness https://emoji-space-rep-client.herokuapp.com/

React, Redux, Node, Express, Mongo

This app will help you to learn the emoji language symbols that easily bridge language barriers, save time, and add emotional nuance easier than with text. Spaced repetition learning helps users retain knowledge easier by testing them more often on the things they forget most frequently.

EXPERIENCE

Blooms Florist / Co-owner

Co-owner of a flower and houseplant shop in Downtown Portland. Developing custom apps to support business services.

Thinkful / Full Stack Developer Apprentice

June 2018 - November 2018 Portland, OR

Completed intensive 50+ hour per week online program. Created and deployed mobile-first applications using best industry practices and software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node, React, React Native, Redux, and algorithms & data structures. Learned new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every day with a senior developer and a team of engineers.

Riot Games / Data Center Engineer

Aug 2011 - March, 2016 Santa Monica, CA

Designed, assembled and managed data center network and server infrastructure across the USA, Japan and Australia to support Riot's growth from 1.4 million daily players in August 2011 to more than 100 million daily players in 2016.

J.Racenstein Company / Technology Manager

June 2007 - June 2009, Carson, CA

Purchased, configured and maintained multi-company servers, Exchange, SQL, VoIP servers, operating systems, network, VPNs, workstations and office equipment.

Developed marketing quiz websites with prize giveaways.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Software Engineering Visual Basic, ASP, MSSQL, Oracle Economics Major Thinkful
Compu College
Carleton College